Guide to the Founders of the Future; Hewlett and Packard Dinner Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Founders of the future; Hewlett and Packard dinner papers
1931-1995
SC0498
Casper, Gerhard
Doyle, Morris.
Freidenrich, John.
Hewlett, William R.
Packard, David, 1912-1996
0.5 Linear feet
Collection includes video tape of the event, text of the speech by Gerhard Casper, color photographs from the event, computer printouts of the exhibit panels on display, copies of historical photographs, and an 1989 booklet on the history of HP. Speakers at the event included John Freidenrich, Morris Doyle, Gerhard Casper, David Packard, and William Hewlett. Edited into the video tape are two videos shown during the event: one piece on the science and engineering quad on campus and FOUNDERS OF THE FUTURE, about Hewlett and Packard and their involvement with Stanford.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
In acknowledgement of their many contributions to Stanford University, including their most recent gift toward the construction of a new science and engineering quad, David Packard and William Hewlett were honored by the University at a dinner event in April, 1995.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes video tape of the event, text of the speech by Gerhard Casper, color photographs from the event, computer printouts of the exhibit panels on display, copies of historical photographs, and an 1989 booklet on the history of HP. Speakers at the event included John Freidenrich, Morris Doyle, Gerhard Casper, David Packard, and William Hewlett. Edited into the video tape are two videos shown during the event: one piece on the science and engineering quad on campus and FOUNDERS OF THE FUTURE, about Hewlett and Packard and their involvement with Stanford.
Access Terms
Photoprints.; Videorecordings.
Collection Contents
- Event materials
  - Video recording, 1995; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Use copy, 1995; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 1U)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Casper, Gerhard speech, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Program and invitation, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Print out of exhibit panels, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Background documentation
  - Source slides (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Test of Time" booklet on H-P, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Source photographs (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Copy prints of historic images pertaining to W. Hewlett, D. Packard, and Stanford, 1931-1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photocopied historical source materials: Stanford classes and commencement (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photocopied historical source materials: post-1940 information including oral histories (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Photocopied historical source materials: David Packard student materials (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photocopied historical source materials: William Hewlett and David Packard gifts (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photocopied historical source materials: William Hewlett's father and background (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Photocopied historical source materials: William Hewlett as trustee (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photocopied historical source materials: David Packard as trustee (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Photocopied historical source materials: William Hewlett and David Packard research associates (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Photocopied historical source materials: William Hewlett student materials (Box 2, Folder 11)